A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 FA739B
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Project report: Ford Foundation program for Saudi Arabia, December 1964 - March 1965. (Reports 005466) (Box 246)
  Public administration -- Management -- Saudi Arabia; Administrative agencies -- Management -- Saudi Arabia; Personnel management -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Survey of airports at Jeddah and Riyadh (Reports 005467), 1963 (Box 246)
  Airport buildings -- Saudi Arabia -- Design; Airports -- Management -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- An analysis of the time system used in Saudi Arabia (Reports 005468), 1964 (Box 246)
  Proposed ministerial decision on the use of standard time by the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.
  Time -- Systems and standards -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Riyadh University library project, phase I (Reports 005469), 1970 (Box 246)
  2 v.;29 p. + appendices
  Academic libraries -- Saudi Arabia; Libraries -- Saudi Arabia; Library administration -- Saudi Arabia; Library buildings -- Saudi Arabia -- Design and construction; Collection development (Libraries) -- Saudi Arabia; Collection management (Libraries) -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation; Jamiat al-Riyad
- Guidelines on organization charting and nomenclature in Saudi Arabian government (Reports 005470), 1966 (Box 246)
  Public administration -- Positions -- Saudi Arabia; Administrative agencies -- Management -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Introduction to study and deliberation differentiating between components of organization by their characteristics and titles 1969. (Reports 005471) (Box 246)
  28 p.: ill., charts
- The development of agricultural cooperative societies in Saudi Arabia: summary report (Reports 005472), 1965 (Box 246)
  Agriculture, Cooperative -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture and state -- Saudi Arabia; Community development -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Tour of twenty thanas December 21, 1970 - January 28, 1971: Impressions of drainage-roads irrigation and co-operatives programmes (Reports 005473) (Box 246)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture, Cooperative -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan -- Statistics; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan; Community development -- Pakistan
- Agricultural development of the Al Hassa Oasis: initiating the operational phase, September 1970. (Reports 005474) (Box 246)
  File memo dated Septemer 30, 1970.
  3, 37 p.: chart
  Agriculture, Cooperative -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture and state -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Zirāʻah wa-al-Miyāh
- Branches and field offices of ministries and agencies (Reports 005475), 1969 (Box 246)
  Public administration -- Management -- Saudi Arabia; Administrative agencies -- Management -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- An evaluation of the economic feasibility and technical requirements for an accelerated wheat production program in Saudi Arabia (Reports 005476), 1970 (Box 246)
  154 p.: tables, graph, map
  Agriculture -- Research -- Saudi Arabia; Wheat trade -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural productivity -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture and state -- Saudi Arabia; Dry farming -- Saudi Arabia; Farm mechanization -- Saudi Arabia; Arid Lands Agricultural Development Program (Ford Foundation); Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Zirāʻah wa-al-Miyāh
- Summary and recommendations: an evaluation of economic feasibility and technical requirements for an accelerated wheat production program in Saudi Arabia (Reports 005477), 1970 (Box 247)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Saudi Arabia; Wheat trade -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural productivity -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture and state -- Saudi Arabia; Dry farming -- Saudi Arabia; Farm mechanization -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Zirāʻah wa-al-Miyāh
- The legislative and judicial sub-systems of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, December 1972. (Reports 005478) (Box 247)
  Legislation -- Saudi Arabia; Judicial process -- Saudi Arabia; Delegation of powers -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation
- Suggested procedures and administrative guidelines for the implementation of a fertilizer subsidy program in Saudi Arabia (Reports 005479), 1971 (Box 247)
  21 p. + attachment: forms
  Fertilizers -- Research -- Saudi Arabia; Dry farming -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture -- Research -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture and state -- Saudi Arabia; Endowments -- Saudi Arabia; Arid Lands Agricultural Development Program (Ford Foundation); Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Zirāʻah wa-al-Miyāh
- Economic evaluation of alternative production possibilities for Al Faisal Settlement Project at Haradh (Reports 005480), 1972 (Box 247)
  42 p.: tables
  Agriculture -- Research -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture and state -- Saudi Arabia; Dry farming -- Saudi Arabia; Arid Lands Agricultural Development Program (Ford Foundation); Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Zirāʻah wa-al-Miyāh
- Selected agricultural statistics, Near East region (Reports 005481), 1972 (Box 247)
  46 p.: principally tables
  Agriculture -- Middle East -- Statistics; Agricultural productivity -- Middle East -- Statistics; Arid lands agriculture -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Summary of reports completed for the Ford Foundation Public Administration Project, Government of Saudi Arabia (Reports 005482), 1966 (Box 247)
  Public administration -- Management -- Saudi Arabia; Administrative agencies -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation
- Report to the Institute of Public Administration on in-service English language training for civil servants 1964. (Reports 005483) (Box 247)
  Arabic translation also on file. The object of the consultation in Riyadh was to determine what form in-service training might take in order to bring about an improvement in the use of English among government employees.
  English languge -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia; Civil service -- Saudi Arabia
- English language training for Saudi Arabian employees (Reports 005484), 1964 (Box 247)
  Executive committee memo dated July 16, 1964.
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia; English language -- Curricula -- Saudi Arabia; English teachers -- Training of -- Saudi Arabia; Educational assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Education and state -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- The English language program for Saudi Arabia 1968. (Reports 005485) (Box 247)
- Evaluation study of the English Language Program for Saudi Arabia (Reports 005486), 1968 (Box 247)
  54 p.: table
  English Language Program
- Memorandum of understanding: English Language Program for Saudi Arabia 1969. (Reports 005487) (Box 247)
- An approach to the teaching of composition (Reports 005488), 1970 (Box 247)
  "[Paper] presented ... at the Ministry of Education, English Language Cener, Riyadh, 29 April 1970." -- T.p.
  26 p. + attachments: ill.
  English language -- Composition (Language arts) -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia -- Curricula; English teachers -- Saudi Arabia -- Training of; Educational assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Education and state -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Maʻārif
- Continuity in English language studies in Saudi Arabia: a major concern (Reports 005489), 1970 (Box 247)
  "Paper prepared for delivery on April 20, 1970 [at the] English Language Center, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia]." -- T.p.
  English language studies in Saudi Arabia: a major concern
- The English-language program in the Institute of Public Administration: a report (Reports 005490), 1970 (Box 247)
  54 leaves: tables
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia; English language -- Curricula -- Saudi Arabia; English teachers -- Training of -- Saudi Arabia; Educational assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Education and state -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation; Maʻhad al-Idārah al-ʻĀmmah (Riyadh, Saudi Arabia)
- Proposed English-language curricula for the Teacher Training College for Women (Reports 005491), 1970 (Box 247)
  English language -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Saudi Arabia; English language -- Curricula -- Saudi Arabia; Women -- Education, Higher -- Saudi Arabia; English teachers -- Saudi Arabia -- Training of; Educational assistance -- Saudi Arabia
- A guide for the English Language Program, Institute of Public Administration (Reports 005492), 1970 (Box 247)
- The elements of the English sentence (Reports 005493), 1970 (Box 247)
  "Adapted from Let's write English, by George T. Wishon and Julia M. Burks." -- T.p.
  311 p.
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; English language -- Curricula -- Saudi Arabia; English teachers -- Training of -- Saudi Arabia; Educational assistance; Education and state -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation; Maʻhad al-Idārah al-ʻĀmmah (Riyadh, Saudi Arabia)
- Guide: the suggested English-language program, Division of Youth Activities, Ministry of Labor (Reports 005494), 1970 (Box 247)
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia -- Curricula; English teachers -- Saudi Arabia -- Training of; Educational assistance; Education and state -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Presenting English (Reports 005495), 1970 (Box 248)
  345 p. + appendix
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia -- Textbooks; English teachers -- Saudi Arabia -- Training of; Educational assistance; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Observations regarding English teaching in intermediate and secondary schools (Reports 005496), 1971 (Box 248)
  English teaching in intermediate and secondary schools
  English language -- Study and teaching (Elementary) -- Saudi Arabia; English teachers -- Saudi Arabia -- Training of; Educational assistance; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Trial of East African English-teaching material in a Riyadh intermediate school, 1972. (Reports 005497) (Box 248)
- Establishing of an intensive English program in the Institute of Public Administration, February 1972. (Reports 005498) (Box 248)
  7 leaves + attachment: ill.
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia; English teachers -- Saudi Arabia -- Training of; Educational assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Education and state -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation; Maʻhad al-Idārah al-ʻĀmmah (Riyadh, Saudi Arabia)
- Learning more English: A Level: the second course for students in the English Language Program of the Institute of Public Administration (Reports 005499), 1972 (Box 248)
  2 v.: 318, 308 p.
  English Language Program of the Institute of Public Administration
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; English teachers -- Saudi Arabia -- Training of; Educational assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Education and state -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation; Maʻhad al-Idārah al-ʻĀmmah (Riyadh, Saudi Arabia)
- Feasibility of an agro-economic survey of Indonesia (Reports 005500), 1965 (Box 248)
  Agro-economic survey of Indonesia
  Agriculture -- Research -- Indonesia; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Indonesia; Agricultural productivity -- Indonesia; Agriculture and state -- Indonesia; Food supply -- Indonesia
- Minorities and public television: an appraisal (Reports 005501), 1973 (Box 248)
  African Americans in television broadcasting; Minorities in television broadcasting -- United States; Public television -- United States; Public broadcasting -- United States; Multiculturalism in mass media; Ford Foundation. Advisory Panel on Minorities and Public Television
- Draft strategy paper on population, August 3 (Reports 005502), 1970 (Box 248)
  Draft of a strategy paper on population sent to FF overseas representatives and population advisors, dated August 3, 1970.
  Birth control -- Developing countries; Population assistance -- Developing countries; Fertility, Human -- Research -- Developing countries; Contraceptives -- Research -- Developing countries; Contraception -- Research -- Developing countries; Social sciences; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Some notes on primary education in Indonesia (Reports 005503), 1970 (Box 248)
  Education -- Administration -- Indonesia; Education and state -- Indonesia; Education, Elementary -- Curriculum planning -- Indonesia; Education, Rural -- Indonesia; Educational planning -- Indonesia; Teachers -- Training of -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Report of Edward M. Bruner on education in Indonesia (Reports 005504), 1969 (Box 249)
  Education, Elementary -- Research -- Indonesia; Education, Higher -- Research -- Indonesia; Education -- Social aspects -- Indonesia; Education and state -- Indonesia; School management and organization -- Indonesia; Teachers -- Training of -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Primary - secondary education and the occupational needs of development in Indonesia (Reports 005505), 1970 (Box 249)
  Education -- Indonesia; Education and state -- Indonesia; Occupational training -- Indonesia; Vocational training -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Recruitment in the Ford Foundation: The search for excellence (Reports 005506), 1972 (Box 249)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Employee selection -- United States; Vocational qualifications -- United States; Ford Foundation Management
- Report on population-related travel, December 13-23 (Reports 005507), 1974 (Box 249)
  File memo dated December 26, 1974.
  Birth control -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Population assistance -- Indonesia; Contraception -- Indonesia; Fertility, Human -- Indonesia; Public health -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Field Office Jakarta
- Two-week consulting assignment in Djakarta July 25 - August 5 (Reports 005508), 1968 (Box 249)
  9 leaves
  Education -- Research -- Indonesia; Religious education -- Curriculum planning -- Indonesia; Teachers -- Training of -- Indonesia; Educational assistance -- Indonesia; Education and state -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Jakarta
- The Ford Foundation and education in Indonesia (Reports 005509), 1970 (Box 249)
  Memo to Paul Booz dated August 6, 1970.
  Education -- Indonesia; Education and state -- Indonesia; Educational assistance -- Indonesia; Education -- Economic aspects -- Indonesia; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Jakarta
- Ford Foundation population activity in Indonesia, FY 1976-77: a preliminary assessment (Reports 005510) (Box 249)
  Memo to Guillaume de Spoelberch dated March 29, 1976.
  Birth control -- Research -- Indonesia; Birth control -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Population assistance -- Indonesia; Contraception -- Indonesia; Fertility, Human -- Indonesia; Public health -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Field Office Jakarta
- American television drama: after "Visions", a blur (Reports 005511), 1978 (Box 249)
  Television programs -- United States -- Reviews; Public television -- United States -- Congresses; Public broadcasting -- United States; Ford Foundation. Office of Communications
- Report of field trip to Makassar, November 28-29 to December 2-4 (Reports 005512), 1969 (Box 249)
  Birth control -- Research -- Indonesia; Birth control clinics -- Indonesia; Population assistance -- Indonesia; Contraception -- Indonesia; Contraceptives -- Indonesia; Fertility, Human -- Indonesia; Public health -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Jakarta
- Report of field trip to Bekasi, Indonesia (Reports 005513), 1969 (Box 249)
  Birth control -- Indonesia; Birth control clinics -- Indonesia -- Management; Contraception -- Indonesia; Contraceptives -- Indonesia; Population assistance -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Jakarta
- Public management-Middle East and Africa: a summary view (Reports 005514), 1972 (Box 249)
  L73-306.
  Conference paper-Dar es Salaam (1973 Aug. 19-22: Tanzania)
  Public administration
- Report to Mr. Clark C. Bloom, the Ford Foundation, on an English language training program in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (Reports 005515), 1964 (Box 249)
  English language training program in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia ...
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia; English language -- Curricula -- Saudi Arabia; Educational assistance -- Saudi Arabia; Education and state -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- The role of the English language in developing countries (Reports 005516), 1969 (Box 249)
  English language in developing countries
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Developing countries; English language -- Curricula -- Developing countries; Education and state -- Developing countries; Occupational training -- Developing countries; Public administration -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Min Riyadh li Riyadh: Safari (Reports 005517), 1970 (Box 249)
  24 leaves
- Memorandum for Mr. McGeorge Bundy (Reports 005518), 1979 (Box 249)
  Account of present status of the European Policy Institute (EPRI).
- Discussion paper on a real estate investment program (Reports 005519), 1967 (Box 249)
  Overview of a plan for investment in the Foundation's new building and other real estate properties in a ten block area in New York City.
  20 p. + attachment.
  Real estate investment program
  Real estate investment -- New York (State) -- New York; Ford Foundation
- Overseas compensation study: final report, September 1969. (Reports 005520) (Box 249)
  Compensation management -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Salaries; Ford Foundation Management
- Study of Ford Foundation library services, April 1971. (Reports 005521), 1976 (Box 249)
  32 p. + appendices: ill., tables, charts, forms
  Library administration; Collection development (Libraries); Acquisitions (Libraries); Interns (Library science); Cataloging; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Management; Ford Foundation Management
- Social insurance, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (Reports 005522), 1970 (Box 249)
  4 p. + attachment
- Research and development for the Ministry of Agriculture and Water, Saudi Arabia (Reports 005523), 1970 (Box 249)
  Memo to Conrad Stucky dated June 23, 1970.
  Agriculture -- Research -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural productivity -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural engineering -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture and state -- Saudi Arabia; Dry farming -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Zirāʻah wa-al-Miyāh
- Proposed salary administration policy and job evaluation plan (Reports 005524), 1971 (Box 249)
  various pagings: tables, forms
  Personnel management -- Saudi Arabia; Employees -- Rating of -- Saudi Arabia; Employees -- Saudi Arabia -- Salaries; Employee fringe benefits -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- A proposed plan for the initial phase of the Law and Development Project (Reports 005525), 1971 (Box 249)
  Memo to Lewis Wagner dated August 12, 1971.
  Law and development project
  Law -- Middle East; Law -- Study and teaching -- Middle East; Law -- Social aspects -- Middle East; Lawyers -- Middle East -- Training of; Public administration -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Field Office Beiruit
- Estimates of revenues by major budget classifications 1389/90 to 1391/92 and by oil and non-oil revenues 1389/90 to 1394/95 (Reports 005526), 1970 (Box 249)
  Petroleum industry and trade -- Saudi Arabia; Fiscal policy -- Saudi Arabia; Finance, Public -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Batrūl wa-al-Tharwah al-Maʻdinīyah
- Accounting development program for the Saudi Arabian government (Reports 005527), 1964 (Box 249)
  Describes the implementation of an accounting system for the Saudi Arabian government.
  Accounting -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Summary of the fiscal management section, Public Administration Project for the Saudi Arabian Government (Reports 005528), 1965 (Box 249)
  16 p.: ill., charts
  Fiscal policy -- Management -- Saudi Arabia; Finance, Public -- Saudi Arabia -- Management; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Saudi Arabia. Wizārat al-Mālīyah wa-al-Iqtiṣād al-Waṭanī; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Government accounting procedures for Saudi Arabia: training course (Reports 005529), 1966 (Box 249)
  Accounting -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Finance, Public -- Saudi Arabia; Fiscal policy -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation
- Summary of budget and a/c systems suggested to be implemented in Saudi Arabia by the FF advisors 1969. (Reports 005530) (Box 249)
  Accounting -- Middle East; Finance, Public -- Middle East; Fiscal policy -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Project and program area evaluation (Reports 005531), 1969 (Box 249)
  Memo to J. Donald Kingsley and Harvey Hall, dated April 30, 1969.
  Accounting -- Saudi Arabia; Finance, Public -- Saudi Arabia; Fiscal policy -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Public Administration Project; Ford Foundation
- Resource and environmental management in the countries of the South: Challenges and opportunities (Reports 005532), 1976 (Box 249)
  07600572
  Chiang Mai University
  Support for research and training in water management in Northern Thailand.
  Agriculture -- Research -- Oceania; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Oceania; Natural resources -- Oceania -- Management; Environmental management -- Oceania; Mahāwitthayālai Chīang Mai
- Classification and pay project, Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan: final report (Reports 005533), 1971 (Box 249)
  11 p. + attachments: chart
  Employees -- Jordan -- Salaries; Personnel management -- Jordan; Civil service -- Jordan -- Salaries; Public administration -- Jordan; Ford Foundation. International Division; Jordan. Civil Service Dept.
- Position classification program implementation in petromin as a trial application for Saudi Arabia (Reports 005534), 1971 (Box 249)